<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://eguar11011.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://eguar11011.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-30T20:22:24+00:00</updated><id>https://eguar11011.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Comprehensive Support and Mutual Aid Group</title><link href="https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2025/Comprehensive_Support_and_Mutual_Aid_Group/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comprehensive Support and Mutual Aid Group"/><published>2025-03-30T11:46:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-30T11:46:00+00:00</updated><id>https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2025/Comprehensive_Support_and_Mutual_Aid_Group</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2025/Comprehensive_Support_and_Mutual_Aid_Group/"><![CDATA[<p align="center"> <img src="/assets/img/blog_1.png" alt="National Univesity of Colombia" width="77%"/> <br/> <span>National Univesity of Colombia - Bogota</span> </p> <p>University is a place for learning, growth, and opportunities for personal and professional development. However, not all students are able to complete their academic journey. Many drop out not only due to academic difficulties but also because of external factors, such as lack of integration into the community, unawareness of available resources, or even a sense of isolation.</p> <p>As a student representative, I witnessed many such cases and felt compelled to drive change. That’s how the <strong>Comprehensive Support and Mutual Aid Group</strong> came to life—an initiative I founded to provide academic support, foster autonomy, and strengthen the student community. This has been a personal project, which means that significantly expanding the group is not feasible. Over time, I have collaborated with others, but most eventually moved on from the project. I have also sought support from professors, but due to their workload, they have been unable to actively contribute to the growth of this initiative.</p> <h2 id="what-is-my-role-in-the-group">What is my role in the group?</h2> <p>For the past two years, I have worked with students at different stages of their education—some for over six months and others for nearly two years. My primary goal has been to reduce dropout rates caused by academic struggles, but my focus extends beyond grades.</p> <h3 id="some-of-the-key-activities-i-carry-out-include">Some of the key activities I carry out include:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Tutoring sessions and Q&amp;A support</strong>: Spaces where students can clarify concepts and reinforce their understanding of various subjects.</li> <li><strong>Participation in hackathons and tech events</strong>: I encourage students to take on new challenges, develop practical skills, and expand their professional networks.</li> <li><strong>Invitations to Google events and other opportunities</strong>: I connect students with events that can enhance their academic and professional growth.</li> <li><strong>Promoting independent learning and curiosity</strong>: I believe that success is not just about knowledge but also about self-confidence. In this group, I push students to explore, investigate, and take ownership of their learning.</li> </ul> <h2 id="a-community">A community</h2> <p>Beyond sharing academic knowledge with students, my greatest hope is that they recognize the true value of the community we have built together. I want them to gain not only knowledge but also the confidence that mutual support and collaboration can make a significant difference in their academic and personal journeys.</p> <h3 id="students">Students</h3> <ul> <li>Daniel Melo</li> <li>Ángel Arévalo</li> <li>Daniel Castillo</li> <li>Jhonatan Sánchez</li> <li>Jvan Herrera</li> <li>Víctor Saa</li> <li>Alejandro Sánchez</li> <li>Sara</li> <li>Santiago Forero</li> </ul> <h3 id="tutor">Tutor</h3> <ul> <li>Eduards Chipatecua</li> <li>Valeria Ramos</li> </ul> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ul> <li>Alvarado, C., Gray, A., Mirza, D., &amp; Tjoa, M. (2021). “The Role of Mentoring in a Dual-Mentored Scalable CS Research Program.” <em>Proceedings of the 52nd ACM Technical Symposium on Computer Science Education (SIGCSE ‘21)</em>, pp. 945–951. DOI: <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/3408877.3432364">10.1145/3408877.3432364</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="support"/><category term="community"/><category term="education"/><category term="mentorship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A personal project aimed at supporting students and strengthening the university community.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">testing</title><link href="https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2025/Test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="testing"/><published>2025-03-30T11:46:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-30T11:46:00+00:00</updated><id>https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2025/Test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2025/Test/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="support"/><category term="community"/><category term="education"/><category term="mentorship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A personal project aimed at supporting students and strengthening the university community.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://eguar11011.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>